1973年埃及和叙利亚突袭以色列
第二天以军地面部队快要溃败
由于以军处于劣势
于是派出一架A-4战机巡逻
还载有一枚核弹
29年后
美国弗吉尼亚韦瑟山
肯定是俄国人？    百分百肯定
- You sure it's the Russians?
- 100%, sir
潜艇有近15兆吨核武，准备出击
Submarine launched 12 to 15
megatons. They went to strike status
罗斯福号击落六枚巡航导弹
The Roosevelt's splashed
six incoming cruise missiles
俄军西移，我们在柏林势孤力弱
The Russians are moving west.
Our Berlin brigade are outnumbered
俄罗斯中部的艾耶斯克亦有威胁
Sir, we've got a launch from Alyesk,
CentrAL Russia
什么威胁？
What the hell is in Alyesk?
SS-18洲际弹道导弹
SS-18 ICBMs
目标是纽约、华盛顿和这儿
Probable targets:
New York, Washington, here
天花坚固吗？    抵御不了直击
- How good is this ceiling?
- Anything but a direct hit
卫星证实有战机，25分钟内施袭
Satellites confirm birds in the air,
first impact estimated 25 minutes
资料准确吗？    准确
- Is that accurate?
- It's accurate
一级紧急状态吧    联络索总统
- I advise we go to DEFCON-1.
- Get President Zorkin on the hotline
他不见了，接报莫斯科发生政变
Zorkin is missing. We have reports
of a coup in Moscow
现在由鲍上将掌权
GenerAL Bulgakov
is cALling the shots now
他究竟是谁？
Who the hell is Bulgakov?
那个想在车臣用核弹的混蛋
The asshole who wanted
to use nukes in Chechnya
进入一级紧急状态，时间无多
Sir, DEFCON-1. We're out of time
动手吧
Do it
总统先生
Mr President
系统在你下令后一分钟才启动
It'll take a minute for the launch
to process after you give the order
下令前，要先核对身分
Before the order can be taken,
an ID check must be performed
数下来第五个号码就是
My ID number is fifth from the top
总统夫人在2104线    谢谢
- Sir, it's your wife on 2104.
- Thank you
请说    要有名单上的人士...
- Yeah.
- The order must be confirmed
下令才能动手    可恶
- by someone on the approved list.
- Shit
国家安全顾问韦真
Gene Revell,
NationAL Security Advisor
要穿礼服？好，我马上来
Is it black tie? OK. I'm on my way
我们可否...
Can we...
改天才继续演习？
... finish this up some other time?
不可以
No
我们得更新这些演习程序
We've got to update these fire drills,
Billy
若有麻烦，我才不要躲到地底去
If the shit ever hits the fan,
I'm not going underground
地底藏有一个核弹
It's a goddamn tomb down there
还要找人对付俄军以外的坏蛋
We have to choose someone else to
face off against besides the Russians
是吗？还有谁有27000枚核弹？
Really? Let's see. Who else has
27,000 nukes for us to worry about?
我是担心那个有一枚核弹的砘
It's the guy with one I'm worried about
我要派人去俄罗斯监察
I have to send some folks to Russia
他们在阿马沙斯解除核武的工作
inspect their nuclear decommissioning
facility at Armazas
是阿尔扎马斯    什么也好
- Arzamas.
- Yeah, whatever
派你的手下去    我亲自去
- Someone from your staff should go.
- I'll go
比利，派人去    我想亲自去
- Billy, send staff.
- I want to go
好吧
OK
别低估老索
Don't underestimate Zorkin.
俄国经济、罪案、车臣...
Between
his economy, crime, Chechnya...
他的肝    所余无几，他怎么样
- His liver.
- What's left of it. How is he?
今天有记者会，他应该能坐起来
He's scheduled a press conference
for today, so we know he can sit up
弗吉尼亚兰利，中情局总部
车臣是俄罗斯的一部分
Chechnya is part of Russia
只有罪犯和其西方朋友想它分裂
Only criminals and their friends
in the West who wish it to be separate
总统先生，请你回去...
Mr President, if you will kindly
come back...
你们有留意到吗？
Do you guys see what I see?
他的西装褛？    本来还扣到钮
- His jacket?
- He used to be able to button it up
他发福了
He's getting fat
我明白那种感受... 看这个
I know how he feels.
Oh, wow. Look at that
也许是另一件褛
Maybe it's not the same jacket
看衣袖，他上次出院时也穿这个
Yeah, it has shiny sleeves. He wore it
the last time he got out of the hospitAL
他没节食    还开酒戒喝个大醉
- He's off the diet.
- And off the wagon. He sIurred...
所以老卓在旁，以免他喝个不停
That must be why Cherlinski is there,
to keep him off the sauce
老卓在哪里？
Where's Cherlinski?
在... 她叫什么？那个棕发的女人
Next to...  What's her name?
The chick with the brown hair
雷莲娜    那不是老卓
- Elena Rishkov.
- That is not Cherlinski
错了，那是老卓
Bzz! Busted. It's Cherlinski
你说的是老查，不是他
You're thinking Cherpitski. It ain't him
那是老卓    不，相信我好了
- I know. It's Cherlinski.
- No, it's not. Trust me
他在莲娜旁边，还在日内瓦胡混
He's next to Elena Rishkov. He was
banging her at the Geneva summit
老卓没去日内瓦，那是老查
Cherlinski was not at Geneva.
Cherpitski was
老查跟雷莲娜有染？
Cherpitski was banging Elena Rishkov?
我只是说老索胖了
I just said Zorkin's putting on weight
为何老扯到性事？真讨厌
Why reduce it to sex? It's disgusting
我同意，记下这个... 若他胖了
I agree. Write it up.
If he is putting on weight
定会影响健康，下午简报写这个
that might have heALth consequences,
so get it in the afternoon brief
找人查是谁搭上莲娜，这有看头
Oh, and somebody find out who is
banging Elena Rishkov. This is good
奥地利，维也纳
车臣要求西方庇护是怎么回事？
What shall we make of Chechnya
asking the West for protection?
这就如漂亮处女想摆脱好色老头
She is like a beautiful virgin, escaping
the cIutches of a lecherous bear
跑去找克林顿帮忙保贞操
and running to Bill Clinton
to save her maidenhood
俗语有云“天下乌鸦一样黑”
A poet once wrote, "Meet the new
boss, same as the old boss."
这也许适合套用在21世纪的欧洲
He could have been writing of us,
of Europe in the 21st century
五十多年来，美、俄一直...
Over 50 years of America and Russia
将其意愿强加在欧洲社会上
imposing their will
on the European community
东、西双方
East and West
都还当我们是小孩
and we're still treated like children...
但却没给我们玩具和糖果
... but without the toys
or the goodnight chocolates
每一天我们都在失去更多...
Each day we lose a little bit more
独立自主，决定未来路向的能力
of our separate sovereign ability
to determine our own futures
而每一天这世界亦更接近小蝴蝶
and each day the world comes just a
little bit closer to that terrible moment
拍动翅膀掀起大风波的可怕时刻
when the beating of a butterfly's wings
unleashes a hurricane...
这个连老天也阻止不了
... God himself cannot stop
这究竟是什么？
So what is it?
你是盲的吗？
Are you blind?
是个炸弹
It's a bomb
那么信管呢？
Where's the fuse?
还是暖的
It's warm
我也是，赶快，时候不早了
So am I. Come on.
I don't have all night
这是个哑弹
It's a dud
快搬它上车
Let's get it on the truck
但怎么把它卖掉？
But how can we sell it now?
总会有人买这种垃圾
There's ALways someone
who'll buy this crap
我最讨厌这些健康问题
I cannot stand all these questions
about my heALth
该形容我“精神爽利又健康”
I am to be described as
"robust" and "heALthy"
是你的还是我的？
Is that yours or mine?
一定是你的，我那个好看不中用
It must be yours. Mine's just for show
不是医院传呼我
It's not the hospitAL
你好    你还在这里
- Hi.
- You're still here
准确点说，应该是你还在这里
Well, I think to be accurate,
it's actually you who's still here
没错
Oh, right
我不是在抱怨
Not that I'm complaining
积克...
Jack...
我知道我们初相识，但是...
I know this is new and all, but...
我有话要说，实在忍不住了
... I have something I have to say
or I'm going to explode
我也不想吓怕你
I don't want you to be scared
什么事？
What?
你爱上了我
You're in love with me
我是医生，懂看病徵的
Jack, I'm a medicAL professionAL.
I can read the symptoms
你确实爱上了我
You're definitely in love with me
这个令你害怕？
And that scares you?
一点都没有
Not even a little
但你却害怕
But I think it scares you
一点都不怕
No, not even a little
话说回来，是你先提起这个
And for the record,
you're the one who brought it up
别管它
Forget it
我要接传呼    不，任由它响吧
- I'm gonna get it.
- No way. It'll stop
我不知道是谁传呼我
I don't know who this is
你谈你的公事    真扫兴
- Just go about your business.
- The timing sucks
你做你该做的，我会体谅
Do what you have to do. I understand
对，我是梅医生
Yes, this is Dr Muller
但你传呼我
Muller. You paged me
喂
Hello
别闹了！我是雷积克
Stop! Yes, this is Jack Ryan
老天！
Jesus
好的，我在半小时内赶到
OK. I'll be there in hALf an hour
我要走了，工作上有急事
I gotta go. I have an emergency
at work
我要走了，对不起
I have to go. I'm sorry
卡丝，今晚一起吃饭好吗？
Cathy, how about dinner tonight?
好的
Yeah
明晚呢？    别得寸进尺
- How about tomorrow night?
- Jack, I said yes to tonight
我知道
I know
历史学家会有什么急事？
What kind of emergency
does a historian have?
他在上午4时20分逝世
He died at 0420 Zulu.
八个半钟后他们有了新总统
81/2 hours
later, they swore in a new president
他是谁？    尼艾历
- Who is he?
- Alexander Nemerov
别说笑，一年前我以他大作文章
You're kidding. I wrote a paper
about him a year ago
说他会当总统    我知道
- I said he could be the next guy.
- I know
没人看过那篇文章    现在有了
- Nobody read it.
- They're reading it now
谁？    老卡
- Who?
- Cabot
我来了14个月，他从未见过我...
I've been here 14 months.
He doesn't know what I look...
你就是雷积克？    是的，局长
- Are you Ryan?
- Yes, sir
怎么回事？是便服日吗？
What is this? "The Paper Chase"?
局长...     快来，我们迟到了
- Sir, my...
- Come on, we're late
你这是越级挑战，所以要听好
You're about to breathe air that's way
over your pay grade, so listen
我会问你意见，记得要小心说话
You'll be asked for advice. Be sure
you know what you're tALking about
不懂的就直说无妨
Don't be afraid to say you don't know
小心措词，那可能会成为政策
Choose your words carefully.
They could become policy
你脱下西装褛
Hey, you. Give me your coat
赶快，稍后还给你
Come on, you'll get it back
领带
Tie
是情报委员会？
So, intelligence committee?
我在电视上看过，但没参加过
I've watched these on C-SPAN.
Never actually been to one
你从未在电视上看过这场面
You've never watched
one of these on C-SPAN
最重要的线报源自克里姆林宫
Our most important assessment comes
from a source inside the Kremlin
线人认为俄军不太听老尼指挥
In his opinion, Nemerov does not owe
his ascension to the military
人人都各有想法
Everyone has opinions, Mr Cabot
我尊重这一点
I respect that
今早我太太说我又老又丑
This morning, my wife woke up
and said I was old, bALd and ugly
那是提问吗？主席
Is that a question, Mr Chairman?
我跟她说外表不是一切
I told her
appearances aren't everything
你同意吗？    当然同意
- Would you agree?
- I certainly would
新总统叫莱艾历吗？
Now, this new fellow, Nezmeroz.
Is that his name?
是尼艾历
Nemerov, sir
虽是线报，但据说他是个强硬派
Despite what your source says,
we hear that Nezmeroz is a hardliner
真有此事吗？
Is he a hardliner?
不
No
这个言之尚早了
It's too soon to make that assessment
据CNN报导
According to CNN
尼总统承诺重建俄罗斯帝国
your Mr Nezmeroz is making promises
to rebuild the Russian empire
于我而言，他太大口气了
That sounds pretty rash
from where I sit
若我在车臣，那我还会更担心
If I were sitting in Chechnya,
I'd be even more worried
老尼只是说他会清除强硬派
Sir, Nemerov only said that
to get the hardliners off his back
若我们不烦他，俄罗斯会更稳定
If we leave him ALone,
Russia will stabilise
我问你意见并不代表你可以开腔
When I asked for your advice, I didn't
mean that you should actually speak
卡局长？
Mr Cabot?
在俄国政府，了解老尼的线人
Some of our assets in the Russian
government who know Mr Nemerov
还没有机会更新情报
have not had a chance to report in
看来花多两天时间搜集更多资料
I'd like to take a couple of days
and gather more information for you
才下定论比较好
before characterising him
但我仍然相信外表是可以骗人的
but I do maintain my opinion
that appearances can be deceiving
那你是说我错了？
You're saying I'm wrong?
当然了，主席
Absolutely, Mr Chairman
我不觉得你样子很丑
I don't think you're ugly
刚才真失礼    参议员不爱惊喜
- I was out of line. I apologise.
- Senators don't like to be surprised
我会作暗示、表态，让他们适应
I hint at what I'm gonna tell them, then
I give them a while to get used to it
然后才告之真相
Then I tell them
我明白    好极
- I understand.
- Good
但老尼的事我说对了
But I'm right about Nemerov
你女朋友喜欢你这么固执？
Your girlfriend like
this stubborn streak in you?
什么？
What?
梅卡丝，第二年住院实习医生
Cathy Muller,
second year surgicAL resident
巴尔的摩纪念医院
BALtimore MemoriAL HospitAL
欢迎你加入中情局
Welcome to the CIA, sport
你的情报不够准，她不算是女友
Your intelligence is a little flawed.
I wouldn't call her my girlfriend... yet
那该是什么？    棒极了的女孩
- What exactly would you call her?
- Great. Amazing
她就是害怕承诺
She's just afraid to commit
他对承诺害怕极了
He's terrified of commitment
约会三次就讲承诺？真是大新闻
A man who's afraid of commitment
after three dates? Alert the media
我知道    他做哪一行？
- I know, I know.
- So what does he do?
他当过海军陆战队，因背伤退役
He was in the marines
before he hurt his back
现在是历史学家    闷蛋
- Now he's a historian.
- Yawn
不，他替一个智囊团做事
No. He works for a think tank
across the river
大闷蛋
Double yawn
丽达，等你今晚见过他再说
All right, Rita. Let's see what you have
to say after we meet him tonight
他...
He's...
英俊吗？
... cute?
手指很粗    卡丝，他有多帅？
- I have fat fingers.
- Cathy! Cute scale, one to ten
我不知道
Oh, God. I don't know
超英俊
Twelve
问他们从哪儿找到这个
Ask them where they found this
在哥兰高地
In the field, in the Golan
73年那儿常打仗，他们在场吗？
There was a lot of fighting there
in 1973. Did they witness it?
这老头说他儿子死掉了
This one says he lost his son
他记得有飞机被击落吗？
Does he remember,
was there a plane shot down?
有，以色列战机被毁
Yes, an Israeli jet, destroyed
这个不值钱
This is worthless
但我会给他四百元... 为了他儿子
But tell him I will give him $400...
because of his son
多... 多谢
Thank... thank you
多谢
Thank you
叙利亚，大马士革
lt's not the sort of thing
you find lying around normally
你怎么找到这个？
- Absolutely not.
- How did you come by it?
在格拉斯哥古老大宅的阁楼
l found her in the attic of an old
mansion house in Glasgow
你这次找到值一千镑的宝物
Your little trip to the attic has got you
a piece worth now about $ 1,000
要是它比较完好，那会更值钱
even in this condition, and had she
been in better condition, even more
好一个发现
A jolly nice find
找到你要的，价钱五千万美元
年份是1973年，以色列制造
12型裂变弹
其实我以为找到一件花园摆设
ln fact, what l thought l'd found
was a garden ornament
是卡丝吗？
Hello, Cathy?
幸好你来电，我赶不及了
Hi. I'm glad you called. I'm running late
你迟半小时来好吗？
Can you come a hALf an hour later?
我不能赴约，对不起
I can't make it. I'm really sorry
临时有急事    什么声音？
- lt's a last-minute work thing.
- What's that noise?
我在飞机上打电话给你
I'm cALling from a plane
我试过找你的    你要去哪里？
- This just came up. l tried to call you.
- Where are you going?
不便相告    积克
- I can't tell you that.
- Jack
你不便相告？
You can't tell me?
积克
Jack
慢着... 怎样？    你在做什么？
- Hold on. Yes, sir?
- What are you doing?
我要取消今晚的约会
I had a date tonight, so I had to cancel
傻瓜，告诉她你为谁出差好了
Don't be stupid. Tell her where you're
going. Tell her who you work for
她会另眼相看
She'll be impressed
好吧，我是替中情局做事的
OK. I work for the CIA
局长要我陪他去俄国检查核武
The director asked me to go with him to
Russia to do a nuclear arms inspection
喂？    这藉口真烂
- Hello?
- That is so lame
我们真的去看他们有否解除核武
I swear, we get to inspect to make sure
they're decommissioning their arsenAL
喂？
Hello?
真是感激不浅
Thanks. Thanks a lot
你好，卡比利
Zdravstvuyte, William Cabot
尼总统
President Nemerov
幸会，总统先生
Pleasure, sir
这是赖太太
May I present Mrs Lathrop
总统先生
Mr President
伦上将    总统先生
- GenerAL Rand.
- Mr President
雷博士    总统先生
- Dr Ryan.
- Mr President
就是你以我为材作有趣的研究
You must be the Dr Ryan who's done
such interesting research on me
你不该感到意外，我们消息灵通
You should not be surprised.
We know quite a bit
说我在大学有很多女友大错特错
We know how wrong your report was
that I had many girlfriends in college
第三年识我太太，自此用情专一
I met my wife in my third year and have
not looked at another woman since
我是指大学头两年... 总统
I was referring to
the first two years... sir
当时你修读英文，成绩优异
Where you received
highest honors in English
我喜欢你
I like you
那么我也一样
Well, in that case, so do I
抱歉打扰你进行检查的工作
I apologise for interjecting myself
in your inspection tour
但我有个口信给霍总统
but I have a message
for President Fowler
你大可以给他电话
You could just call him on the phone
我想由他的老朋友转告口信
I would like him to hear it from you,
his friend of many years
我要亲自见你
who received it personally from me
让你看到我的表情和身体语言
and saw my expression and the
language of my body as I spoke it
我明白的
I understand
车臣是我国的内政
Chechnya is an internAL affair
我们的做法与你们无关
What we do there should be
none of your concern
我会传这口信，但他该不会同意
I will relay the message,
but I don't think he will agree
本国有人想借此来削减我的势力
Some people in my country
will use this issue to weaken me
我国却有人说
Some people in my country say
车臣之战正是你的弱点所在
your war in Chechnya
is exactly your weakness
车臣全国满是罪犯、坏蛋
Chechnya is a nation of criminALs
每天都作懦夫所为，伤害百姓
Every day brings another cowardly
attack on innocent Russian citizens
这问题不用贵国担心
It is none of your concern
我们担心政局的稳定性
Stability is our concern
我们担心车臣是否太平
Peace in Chechnya is our concern
还容我直说...
And, if I may speak frankly...
我们也担心你对俄军的控制力
... your control over your military
concerns us too
你来这儿... 就如搞人家的老婆
For you to get involved here, it's... like
sleeping with another man's wife
而你所建议的是事后...
And what you are suggesting
is that afterward
他们能相安无事，和平共处
they can all live together
under the same roof
但关键是戴了绿帽的丈夫买了枪
But what really happens is
the betrayed husband buys a gun
会面顺利    老尼身旁的是谁？
- That went well.
- Who's the guy with Nemerov?
古东尼    前苏联特务？
- Anatoli Grushkov.
- OId KGB?
他是老臣子，没人敢动他分毫
He's been around since Brezhnev.
Nobody's had the guts to get rid of him
因为他知道尸体葬在哪里？
Because he knows
where the bodies are buried?
也许是他亲手下葬的
He probably buried them himself
我们有阿尔扎马斯科学家的名册
And we were able to obtain a roster
of their scientists at Arzamas
列明他们的身分、专长
Who's who, what their expertise is
阿尔扎马斯十六区
Arzamas-16 is home
是俄国实验物理学科研所之乡
to the All-Russian Scientific Research
Institute of ExperimentAL Physics
也是我国首个原子弹的出生地
and is the birthplace
of our first atomic bomb
不少伟大科学家还在这里工作
Many of our greatest scientists
worked here and many still do
自1995年...
Since 1995
我们已拆除逾一万个核武装置
we have dismantled
over 10,000 nuclear devices
多年来我们千方百计想进来这儿
We tried so hard to get in here
over the years
我派了三个人来
I sent three people
他们都为此牺牲
They all died trying
T血上写着什么？
What does the T-shirt say?
我是炸弹专家，见我跑... 跟着跑
"I am a bomb technician. If you
see me running... try to catch up."
好的
OK
抱歉打岔，但我要问一件小事
Sir, I'm sorry. Just one quick thing.
I'm sure it's nothing
这个说今天该有17位科学家当值
According to this, there are
17 senior scientists on duty today
我只数到14位
I only count 14
三位博士，分别姓米、奥、史的
Doctors Milinov, Orlov and Spassky
他们都不在这里
They don't seem to be here
这个我会查清楚
I will make inquiries
米博士病了，奥博士放假
Dr Milinov is out sick.
Orlov is on vacation
史博士... 很不幸已过世了
Spassky, I'm grieved to say,
was killed
上周开车上班时遇上意外
driving his car to work
just this past week
我们继续吧？
We move on, shall we?
这边走
Please
真棒，这一切你都记得一清二楚
Very impressive. You ALmost seem
to have that information memorised
早料到你会问这个
I assumed you would ask, Dr Ryan
以色列  海法
我们九点半落机，叫他来会合
We touch down at Andrews at 2130.
Tell him to meet me there
局长，那三位没出现的科学家
Sir? Those three missing scientists
姓米的擅长造雷管
Milinov's expertise is detonators
姓史的善于造核子实
Spassky's expertise
is the nuclear core
姓奥的是个数学家
Orlov is a mathematician
擅长计算裂变弹的炸药用量
whose expertise is the geometry of
high explosives inside a fission bomb
要造核弹就要找这三个人
The exact three men you would need
if you wanted to build a bomb
老古说...     老古是个大话王
- Grushkov said...
- Grushkov's a liar
姓米的没病，姓奥的没放假
Milinov is not sick.
Orlov hardly ever takes a vacation
撞车死掉的史博士根本不懂开车
and Spassky, who's supposed to have
died driving a car, doesn't drive
他们不知道这三人的下落
They have no idea
where these guys are
但你却无所不知
I'm dying to ask you how you know
是克里姆林宫的线报
Secure source inside the Kremlin
代号斯纳加
Codename Spinnaker
我们互通情报
He gives me stuff, I give him stuff
打开秘密渠道，以免灾难发生
We keep the back channels open
in hopes of staving off disaster
说起灾难，你联络了女友没有？
And speaking of disaster,
did you call your girlfriend yet?
不，我不知道该怎样解释
No. I don't know how to get out of this
请她出席周日晚白宫的记者晚宴
All right. Invite her to the White House
correspondents dinner Sunday night
那是城中的盛会
It's the hottest ticket in town
好主意，我如何入场    相信我
- Sounds great. How do I get in?
- Trust me
在车上再见
I'll see you at the car
还喜欢你的文职工作吗？
Still loving your desk job?
是的
Yeah, I am
你的俄语还管用吗？
How's your Russian?
还管用，为什么？
Still works. Why?
俄国科学家失踪，要找他们下落
Three Russian nuclear scientists are
missing. I need to know where they are
我不再做这种工作了
I wasn't doing this any more
我只是想要这些资料，约翰
I just need information this time,
Johnny
指令在机上，十一点半起飞
Your orders are on the plane.
Wheels up at 2330.
祝旅途愉快
Have a nice flight
周日晚八点，希尔顿酒店
Sunday night, 8.00, at the Hilton.
请帖本是勒约翰的
The
tickets are in the name of John Clark
你有礼服吧？    有的，局长
- You do have a tux?
- Yeah, yes, sir
我的妻子茱莉来自新泽西
My beautiful wife, Julie, is from
New Jersey.
有15张选举团选票
15 electorAL votes
大家都知道她是半个犹太人
And is, as you know, hALf-Jewish
所以我们把佛州25张票平分
so we'll take Florida's
25 electorAL votes and divide by two
这酒店很棒    很华丽
- This is a nice hotel.
- Yeah. Beautiful
丽达曾入住这酒店... 说很不错
My friend Rita stayed here once.
She said it was... nice
也许晚宴结束后...
Maybe after dinner we can...
我们在这里租一间房
... we can get a room here
我已订了房间
I ALready did
你没有    我有
- You didn't.
- Yes, I did
我曾在多个场合抽过大麻
... I did, on a handful of occasions,
smoke marijuana
加州，54张选举团选票
California, 54 electorAL votes
莫斯科时间六点钟，俄军向车臣
At 0600 Moscow time, the Russians
launched a massive artillery strike
首都格罗兹尼施以猛烈炮击
against Grozny,
the capitAL of Chechnya
炮弹含有实验性化武神经性毒气
The shells contained an experimentAL
chemicAL weapon, a nerve agent
依图片所示，20分钟后毒气扩散
Saturation, you can see
on the sat photos, took 20 minutes
方圆12哩内的所有人都会...
after which every person
inside a radius of 12 miles
欲救无从，出现大脑麻痹的症状
was rendered helpless by symptoms
approximating late-stage cerebrAL pALsy
老天    死了多少人？
- Oh, my God.
- How many dead?
该有八成人
Best guess, 80%
老尼发动历来最大型的生化战
Nemerov launched the biggest attack
in the history of chemicAL warfare
谈对策吧    最糟的是毫无对策
- Let's tALk response.
- The worst thing we can do is nothing
若他得逞，下次会是核战吧？
If he gets away with chemicAL weapons,
what's next? BiologicAL, nuclear?
除了以毒攻毒，还有什么法子？
OK. Short of gassing the Kremlin,
what's the strongest response?
派出和平部队    车臣没有主权
- We send in peacekeepers.
- Chechnya's not sovereign
他们想建立地位，我们如其所愿
They requested recognition, so we
give it. Not fulI diplomatic, provisionAL
于是车臣要求协助，我们就派军
Then the Chechens request assistance
and we send in peacekeepers
怎样去那儿    从土耳其飞过去
- How do you get them in there?
- We fly them in from Turkey
飞越美国领空？
- Over Armenian air space?
他们不会介意打俄国
- To screw Russia? They won't complain
动手吧，还老尼一点颜色
Let's do it. Nemerov can choke on it
比利？
Bill?
雷博士    是的，局长
- Dr Ryan.
- Yes, sir
你有何高见？
What do you think?
守旧派会建议
ConventionAL wisdom suggests
老尼沿用旧有方法，老调重弹
that Nemerov is playing
the traditionAL Russian role:
要有野心，扩展势力，威吓全球
be aggressive, flex your muscles,
dare the world to stop you
但老尼不吃这套    他是强硬派
- But Nemerov isn't conventionAL.
- He acts like a hardliner
无意冒犯，我不同意这看法
With respect, I don't think he is one
他刚攻打别国首都，所以你错了
He just gassed the capitAL of another
country. With respect, you're wrong
为何浪费时间？
- So what are we wasting our time for?
若不是他下令的呢？
- What if he didn't order the attack?
若不是他下令攻车臣呢？
What if Nemerov
didn't order the attack?
如果是掌权的上将在搞鬼呢？
What if it was a... a rogue generAL?
或是党军不满赶不走市内的叛兵
Or a military unit frustrated they
couldn't get the rebels out of the city?
你有实据支持此说还是在胡扯？
Have you reason to believe he didn't
order it, or are you just floating this?
你不能肯定
You don't know
该是这样，我敢说他没下令施袭
I don't think he did it, sir.
I would bet he didn't do it
请高级官员多留一会儿？
Will senior staff remain behind
for a few minutes, please?
俄罗斯新任总统尼艾历...
Russia's newly-installed president,
Alexander Nemerov
刚开始发表演说，以下是直播
has just begun to address the state.
We join him in progress
十年来我们一直对抗...
For ten years now,
we have contended...
麻烦你开大声点？
Excuse me. Could you turn that up?
伤害无辜的俄罗斯百姓
... toward innocent Russian citizens
终于...
Finally...
每一个国家都有权自卫
... every nation has a right
to defend itself
这种恐怖活动必须被遏止
This terrorism must end
轰炸车臣... 是我的决定
The bombing of Chechnya...
was my decision
做得好，醒目仔
Nice going, ace
是谁做的？
Who did it?
皮上将、苗上将，共产老头不悦
GenerAL Pildysh, GenerAL Mitkin.
Unhappy old Communists
混蛋
Bastards
解除其军职    我会亲自杀他们
- Relieve them of command.
- I will shoot them myself
使他们消失就是
Just disappear them
处决他们会显得我不是大权在握
Their execution would tell the world
I didn't have control
现在表现内疚比表现无能为佳
These days, better to appear guilty
than impotent
我们的俄国朋友受到影响吗？
How is our Russian friend
affected by this?
没有，我仍然支持这个计划
I am not affected.
I remain devoted to our little plan
以你的收费，我才不感到意外
At what you're charging us,
I am not surprised
美国佬呢？    马先生相信我们
- And the American?
- Mr Mason is a believer
我已多存了一点钱进他的户口
I put a little extra
in the escrow account for him
为什么？    他不会有太长的命
- Why?
- He won't live long enough to get it
货呢？    一周前从海法寄出
- Where is the package?
- It left Haifa a week ago
早就说这些东西可以致命
I'm told these things can kill you
但是事情有变
But so much has changed
也许在新形势上该用... 新方法？
Perhaps the new situation suggests
we consider... a different approach?
也许试着令俄罗斯融入欧洲
Maybe try to bring Russia
more into Europe
更接纳我们的想法？
more into our way of thinking?
这个我们早已讨论过
We have discussed that,
Monsieur Monceau
而且你也同意不那么做
and with your concurrence, rejected it
也许我们这次太鲁莽
Oh. Perhaps we were hasty
也许计划...     怎样？
- Perhaps our plan is...
- Is what?
进行得不顺利
Not perfectly conceived
你疯了吗？全世界的右翼组织...
Are you crazy? All over
the world, right-wing parties
民族主义者、纳粹、反犹太国家
nationalist movements,
Nazis, Aryan Nations
首次并肩合作
all working together for the first time
这还不算顺利？
Is that not perfect?
我尊重朋友们的意愿和判断
Well, I respect the will and judgment
of my friends
但这周发生的事令我...
But in light of the week's events,
I am grown...
对这计划失去信心
... uncomfortable with this plan
所以我必须... 请辞了
So I must... beg your leave
各位再见
Gentlemen
哈夫会送你出去
Herr Haft will help you out
你的颈巾
Your scarf, monsieur
马里兰，巴尔的摩
小心开这个，否则会害死人
Watch it with that thing.
You're gonna kill somebody
你好吗？阿马
Yo, what's up, Mason?
我一直想问你在哪里弄这个纹身
You know, I ALways wanted to ask
you...  Where'd you get that tat, man?
海军
The navy
海军？我也曾当过海军
The navy? I was in the navy
在医务船六年，你呢？
HospitAL ship, six years. You?
八个月
Eight months
你退役了？
Oh. You wash out?
好吧，兄弟，晚安
All right, brother.
You have a good one
好的，兄弟
Yeah, brother
大日子来临了，多谢
没发觉其他国家会以我们为榜样
... not realising the rest of the world is
watching and will take a cue from us...
车臣遭受空前残暴的袭击
The unprecedented attack
on Chechnya
显示俄政府新班子面对不稳之局
signals a dangerous
and troubling shift in Russian policy
西方需作出最强硬鲜明的反应
lt demands the toughest and most
unambiguous response from the West
北约和平部队正前往车臣
NATO forces are on their way to
Chechnya to serve as peacekeepers
为这个大灾难的受害者提供援助
and to provide humanitarian aid
to victims of this monstrous...
早料到会如此
I expected this
是吗？
Really?
你会怎么做？
What will you do?
没什么
Nothing
我们什么都不做
We will do nothing
照片拍了四个钟
These are four hours old
俄军第12、15、2坦克团
Russian
12th, 15th and 2nd tank regiments
为何有调动？
Why haven't they moved?
老尼不会这么笨    但他已表态
- Nemerov's too smart to move them.
- He speaks
他有近两万部坦克，北约无得比
Jack, Nemerov's got, like, 19,000
tanks. No way NATO can match that
所以他才不会调动坦克
That's why he's not gonna move them
这就像下棋，要事先部署好
It's like chess.
He's thinking three moves ahead
北约说我们只能用核武克制他
The NATO playbook says we can only
stop him with tacticAL nuclear weapons
他才不会为此引发核战
And he won't risk a nuclear war
over this
他该是有所暗示，他没攻击车臣
I ALso think he's sending us
a message. He didn't bomb Grozny
俄罗斯，阿尔扎马斯十六区
打扰了，请问史老太太在哪儿？
Excuse me.
I'm looking for Mrs Spassky
在走廊尽头那边
At the end of the corridor
毕业后我没见他了
I haven't seen Sasha since university
你是他的助教？我却记不起你
And you were his teaching assistant?
Strange, I don't remember you
他知道我在这区，叫我来探望你
When he heard I was in Arzamas,
he asked me to look in on you
他说带我去西方    所费不菲
- He says he'll take me to the West.
- That would require a lot of money
这儿赚不到钱，可去别处赚
Just because the imbeciles here pay
him nothing doesn't mean others won't
他有一份秘密工作
He has a secret job
替政府做事？
For the government?
替有钱的笨蛋做事
For imbeciles with money
同一番废话，做这个，别做那个
Same nonsense, do this, don't do that
他们还叫他别联络母亲
They even told him
not to call his mother
混蛋
The pigs
我随时归西，他却不能来电话
I could die any day
and he can't phone his mother
但我的儿子好孝顺
But my Sasha, he called
昨晚才来过电话
Just last night
阿勒取得她的号码
Clark got us her number
安全局追查得到电话从这儿打出
NSA traced
calls to that number back to here
克列缅兵格水库的前苏联基地
It's an abandoned Soviet army base
on the Kremenchug reservoir
三个俄国科学家在乌克兰干嘛？
What are three Russian atomic
scientists doing in Ukraine?
该是在制造核弹
A fair guess, they're building a bomb
老尼有无数核弹，为何建这个？
Nemerov has thousands of bombs.
Why would he build a secret one?
为了否认一切
Deniability
秘密造一个，然后偷运去车臣
Build one nobody knows about, he can
drive it to Chechnya in his Beemer
无法追查，瞒天过海
No way to track it, no way to trace it
他可以引爆核弹，然后矢口否认
He could set it off and say,
"I didn't do it."
无意冒犯，但这说不通
With respect, I don't think
that adds up
说得通，只是你不喜欢这结果
It adds up. You just don't like
what it adds up to
铀腐蚀的热度
Ah, the warmth of plutonium decay
这个腐蚀严重，幸好你有戴手套
It's completely corroded.
At least you're wearing gloves
有人想抽一根美国烟吗？
Anyone want to light up
an American cigarette?
你这疯子
You're crazy
我出去吸烟
I'm going out
要更换炸药块
The explosive blocks
must be replaced
配置经过精密计算的系统
Machined to a thousandth
of a millimetre
细小至千分之一毫米
in a mathematically determined
configuration
可造核弹吗？    首先要分析...
- Do we have a bomb?
- First we must analyse the yield...
可造核弹吗？
Do we have a bomb?
可以
Yes
可造核弹
Yes, we do
这是一个... 考验
This is a... a test
接电话吧
Answer it
快去    真的要我接？
- Answer it.
- Are you sure?
喂？
Hello?
是的
Yes
是的，局长
Yes, sir
我要出去一会儿
I have to go outside for just a second
好吗？我马上回来
OK? I'll be right back
很快回来
I'll be right back
我负责写报告    你有当兵经验
- Sir, I write reports.
- I reviewed your military records
懂得自卫    对，但我不是特务
- You can take care of yourself.
- Yes, sir. But I'm not trained for that
你要做我的耳目，不是做特务
I'm not asking you to be an operations
officer, just my eyes and ears
我不能亲自出马
I can't go
那么... 这行动未经批准
So... this isn't sanctioned
这个交给阿勒，拿他的情报回来
I want you to give this to Clark,
see what he finds out, bring it home
是的，局长
Yes, sir
积克...
Jack...
我们从未有过这番对话
... we never had this discussion
什么对话？
What discussion?
乌克兰，克列缅兵格水库
阿勒... 三天前
OK. Clark...  So this is
three days ago
这儿有车，这两处有守卫
It shows vehicles here.
Guards here and here
我也该买一部这个
I gotta get one of those
红外线卫星在34小时前拍到这个
Now, the infrared satellite
took this photograph 34 hours ago
显示这两处有守卫
That shows guards here and here
我甚至不用电邮
I don't even have e-mail
检查站有两人，军营有二至五人
There are two at the checkpoint,
between two and five in the barracks
两人有武器，而我们会在这里
and two with the package,
which we believe to be here
没问题，给我两个人和麻醉枪
No problem. Give me a couple
of guys, some tranquilliser darts
六分钟就可以离开
we can be out in six minutes
有问题的    什么问题？
- There is a problem.
- What's that?
这是昨天的情形，一个守卫都无
This is yesterday.
No guards visible at all
那为何是个问题？
Why is that a problem, Mr Ryan?
两个原因，糟的是看不见敌人
For two reasons. Either we can't
see them, which is bad
更糟的是他们已走，我们来迟了
or worse, they left, and we're too late
快换衫
Suit up
什么？    你不能穿成这样
- What?
- You can't go dressed like that
不，我是分析员，不做特务工作
No, no. I'm an anALyst.
I don't go on missions
放心，007，这只是侦察工作
Relax, 007. It's not a mission.
It's just a recce
随你怎么说，我只负责写报告
OK, fine, whatever you call it.
I don't do that. I just write reports
那就为此写报告，换衫
OK. So write a report about it. Suit up
阿勒，不行
Clark, no
Clark... no
老卡说你代我出席记者晚宴
So, Cabot tells me you got my ticket
to the correspondents dinner
好玩吗？我从未见过那种大场面
Have a good time?
I've never been to one of those
其实我满怀期待赴会的
I was actually looking forward to it
不，我不会进去
Clark, no. I'm not going in there
当然，你留在这里帮我看这只艇
Goddamn right. You're gonna stay here
and make sure no one steALs my boat
马上就回来
Be right back
糟了
Damn
海法
老天
Oh, Jesus
真是的，入境处没通知你们吗？
Oh, God. Immigration didn't
call you guys, huh?
抱歉，会说英语吗？
I'm sorry. You speak English?
我不会说乌克兰话
I don't speak much Ukrainian
别误会，我是美国公民有证件...
It's not what you think. I'm an
American citizen. I have my papers...
好了，不出示证件
OK. No papers
请你把抢放下
Please. Just put the gun down
电筒？你想我把它放下？
The light? You want
me to put the light down?
别胡来，我会把电筒放下
OK. Take it easy.
I'll put the light down
好了，我把电筒放下
Here we go, I'm putting it down
开枪，积克
Shoot him, Ryan
快开枪
Shoot him
趁他未猜出我说什么，快开枪
Shoot him before he figures out
what I'm saying
叫他们脱鞋    什么？
- Get their shoes.
- What?
叫他们脱鞋
Tell them to take their shoes off
你会说乌克兰话    你不懂？
- You speak Ukrainian.
- Yeah. You don't?
他们喷油的东西该有雪柜那么大
Whatever it is they were spray painting
was big, about the size of a fridge
印痕很深，所以我们知道三件事
The imprint it left was deep.
So we know three things
它很重，有辐射性，还不见了
It was heavy, something was
radioactive, and now it's gone
其中一人说英语？    南非人
- One of them spoke English?
- South African
那他在乌克兰跟三个俄国科学家
So, what's a South African
doing in the Ukraine
和一个以色列货箱有何关系？
with three Russian scientists
and a crate from Israel?
我会去海法找老卡    事不宜迟
- Tell Cabot I'll call him from Haifa.
- I have a feeling you better hurry
不少人认为20世纪是共产主义
Most people believe the 20th century
was defined by the death struggle
和资本主义之争
of communism versus capitalism
而法西斯主义只是昙花一现
and that fascism was but a hiccup
如今我们更有体会
Today we know better
共产主义徒劳无功
Communism was a fool's errand
马克斯的追随者不见影踪
The
followers of Marx, gone from this earth
但希特勒的信众则日益增强
But the followers of Hitler
abound and thrive
不过希特勒生不逢时
Hitler, however,
had one great disadvantage
当时法西斯主义像病毒般散播
He lived in a time when fascism,
like a virus
好比爱滋病病毒
like the AlDS virus
要有强大的受体以便散播
needed a strong host in order to spread
德国正是这个受体
Germany was that host
可是即使德国强大，但还是失败
But strong as it was,
Germany could not prevail
这世界太大了
The world was too big
幸好世界改变了
Fortunately, the world has changed
全球通讯、有线电线、互联网
Global communications,
cable TV, the internet
如今世界变小了
Today the world is smaller
而病毒不用强大受体帮助扩散
and the virus does not need
a strong host in order to spread
这种病毒...
This virus...
可在空气中散播
... is airborne
还有一点，别让人家说我们疯狂
One more thing.
Let no man call us crazy
他们说希特勒疯狂，其实他是笨
They called Hitler crazy, but Hitler
wasn't crazy. He was stupid
你不用跟美俄对敌
You don't fight Russia and America
令美俄打起来就是
You get Russia and America
to fight each other
令他们互相残杀
and destroy each other
有何发现？    乌克兰出口贸易
- What did you find?
- Ukraine's exports are online
我查过这两周的运货单
I pulled up the shipping manifests
那货箱在十天前送抵基辅机场
The only crate that size was picked up
at Kiev InternationAL ten days ago
再运去加那利群岛
and flown to the Canary Islands
空军有核武评估小组，叫他们...
The air force has a nuclear
assessment team. Call them...
那货箱上了货机，送去东岸了
Jack, it got put on a cargo freighter,
headed for the East Coast
什么？    巴尔的摩，送来这儿
- What?
- Baltimore. lt's coming here
飞船外景色一流，球赛快将开始
lt's a great view from the Budweiser
blimp as we count down to game time
赛前活动多姿多采
We'll have the pre-game festivities
而全国头号球迷也快将到场
as well as the arrival of the nation's
number one football fan in a moment
誓要达成目标
Then conquer we must
全因这是正义的使命
For our cause it is just
我们以此为座右铭
And this be our motto
相信上帝
ln God is our trust
满布星号的旗帜
And the star-spangled banner
永远飘扬
Forever shall wave
在自由的国土上...
O'er the land of the free...
快联络值勤官！
Get me the duty officer!
勇者之乡
Home of the brave
各位，有请美国总统
Ladies and gentlemen,
the President of the United States
霍罗拔！
Robert Fowler!
要出场了
Showtime
可恶
Shit
15码罚球，第一个死球
15 yard penalty, first down
打得好！
That's the way!
混帐
Shit
喂
Hello
喂？    局长！
- Hello?
- Sir!
喂？    局长！
- Hello?
- Sir!
该死！
Shit!
卡比利    是积克
- Cabot.
- It's Ryan
什么事？    核弹已送来
- What?
- The bomb is in play
搜索队20分钟后在码头跟我会合
The AFRAT team are meeting me at
the docks in 20 minutes to try to find it
什么码头？    巴尔的摩
- What docks?
- BALtimore
什么？你说什么？    巴尔的摩
- You're breaking up. What did you say?
- Baltimore
我待会给你电话    巴尔的摩
- I'm losing you. I'll call you back...
- Baltimore
局长！
Sir!
欢迎莅临巴尔的摩球场
阿尊、红组、绿组，快走！
John! Red-Green! Let's go! Let's go!
快送总统走！
Move it! Let's go!
赶快！快走！
Move! Go, go, go, go! Move!
怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
俄国佬制造了核弹，还送来这儿
Some Russian scientists made a
nuclear bomb. It's arrived in BALtimore
快疏散观众    趴下来！
- Get those people out of the stadium.
- Stay down!
总统突然被护送离场
The President has been taken
off the field
407号    劳驾
- 407.
- Thanks, JJ
显然发生了大规模的爆炸
Clearly something has happened
of tremendous proportions
起因不明，但空中有一大团云...
We have no word as to what but
there is an enormous cloud over...
快走！
Go, go, go!
总统先生，你没事吧？
Mr President! Are you all right?
他被困在车内，走开
He's stuck. Get out of the way
总统先生，你没事吧？
Mr President, are you all right?
你没事吧？我们是海军陆战队
Are you all right, Mr President?
This is the marines, sir
丹尼，过来帮忙
I need your help, Danny
艾华，快拿担架来！
AIvarez, get me a stretcher, now!
你拿担架来
You got the stretcher?
你拿担架来    不用了
- You got the stretcher?
- No, I don't want one
快走...
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
快走！
Move it!
赶快！行了！起飞！
Go, go! Close them off! Go on up!
总统先生...
Mr President...
美国发生核爆，请你马上来
There's been a nuclear explosion in
America. You must come with us now
什么？
What?
不知谁在搞鬼，但肯定不是我们
We don't know who or how.
But it wasn't us
继格罗兹尼... 你希望不是我们做
After Grozny you hope it wasn't us
正草拟一份声明让你作强烈否认
We are drafting
a strong deniAL for you
还要表示慰问的
And a statement of sympathy
尤里... 下令三军作好戒备
And Yuri... order all military
on the alert
是积克！
Hey! It's Ryan
你在哪里？    巴尔的摩市外
- Jack, where are you?
- Somewhere outside BALtimore
老卡救了总统    他在哪儿？
- Cabot got the President out.
- Where is he now?
他会留在飞机上
They're taking him airborne, on NAOC
上头认为应该是俄军做的好事
They think it might be the Russians
不是，我要找老卡，帮我联络他
It wasn't the Russians. I gotta tALk to
Cabot. Patch me through to the plane
他不在机上
Cabot's not on the plane
他下落不明，一小时后你再来电
We don't
know where he is. Call back in an hour
时间无多，总统随时准备还击
We don't have an hour. Fowler's
gonna want to hit back now
要赶快向他证明这不是俄军做的
Listen. We have to prove it wasn't the
Russians before he's convinced it is
你可以回来兰利吗？
Can you get back to Langley?
没时间，辐射评估小组在哪里？
There's no time. The radiation
assessment team, where are they?
市区南面的斯谭拿隧道
Stambler Tunnels, south of the city.
Stambler Tunnels, south of the city
市区南面的斯谭拿隧道
正在吹盛行风，东、北还有落尘
The prevailing winds are blowing
the fallout to the east and north
你留在南面就较安全
As long as you stay south you're OK
你没事吧？    你说呢？
- Mr President, are you all right?
- How the hell do you think I am?
有多少伤亡？    不知道
- How many casuALties?
- We don't know
核弹怎么来的    雷达侦测不到
- How the hell did it get there?
- We don't know. Radar didn't pick it up
老卡呢？他在哪里    我不知道
- Well, how is Cabot? Where is he?
- I don't know
那你知道什么？    我一无所知
- What do you know?
- I don't know, all right? I don't know!
我一无所知！
I don't know!
康达没上机    派搜索队去找
- GenerAL, Kondor is not on board.
- Send the AFRAT team
总统，我建议进入二级紧急状态
Mr President, I recommend
we move to DEFCON-2
我们的情报如何？
Where's our intelligence?
俄国空军防御处于最高戒备状态
Russian air defences
are at their highest level
他们或怕遇袭，我拉不开这张椅
Maybe they're afraid of being attacked.
I can't get this goddamn chair open!
准备起飞
We're about to take off
不知是谁搞鬼    应该是俄军...
- We don't know who did it...
- We think the Russians...
该是？    进入二级紧急状态吧
- You think?
- Sir, DEFCON-2
我们在揣测...     都是废话！
- We're groping in the dark...
- This is too much goddamn bulIshit!
还不够证据
And not enough fact
弹坑有100至150码阔
The blast crater is about
100, 150 yards wide
这核弹威力不是太大
which suggests a low-yield device
比落在广岛的原子弹还要小
quite a bit smaller
than the Hiroshima bomb
球场周围四分一平方哩之地被毁
A quarter of a square mile
around the stadium is just gone
外围的大厦没倒塌，但损毁严重
Beyond that, buildings remain, heavily
damaged, for another quarter mile
离核爆区越远，破坏越小
The damage tapers off the farther
you get from Ground Zero
都宾
Dubinin
哈夫去了美国，现在就靠你了
Herr Haft has left for America.
Now we are counting on you
我保证我物有所值
I assure you,
I will earn every pfennig
立正！
Attention
你们也知道美国发生核爆
You've heard of the bomb in the USA
但你们不知道15分钟前
What you haven't heard
is that 15 minutes ago
美国发射洲际弹道导弹攻莫斯科
an American ICBM hit Moscow
我们要打美军在北海的航空母舰
We are to retaliate against an American
aircraft carrier in the North Sea
快准备出动
Man your aircraft
灰烬没有辐射性
The ash isn't radioactive.
盛行风把落尘吹向大海
The winds
are blowing the fallout to sea
上尉，中情局雷积克
Captain. Jack Ryan, CIA
冼罗娜，你要在外边等
Lorna Shiro. You need to wait outside
把你对核弹所知的都告诉我
I need to know all you know
about the bomb
我们在采集样本，明天会有公布
We're collecting samples. Get in line
and we'll have the report out tomorrow
上尉，我要知道核弹从哪儿来的
Captain, I need to know now
where this bomb came from
或是它不是从哪来，否则没明天
or even where it didn't come from
or there may not be a tomorrow
混帐，阿韦，你在哪里？
Shit. Wesson, where are you?
离核爆区四分之一哩
About a quarter mile from Ground Zero
已尽力而为，脚板快被烤熟了
This is about as far as we'll go.
My feet are sizzling
辐射度接近装备所能抵御的上限
I'm getting rads
nearly the limit of our gear
小队马上撤退    收到
- OK. Cut the rover loose and get out.
- Roger that
装核弹的货箱在码头该有人签收
Dillon, the crate the bomb was shipped
in. Somebody had to sign for it at port
海关定有记录，老卡在哪里？
Customs must have a database.
Get me a name. Where's Cabot?
不知所踪，我们在查看各医院
No one knows.
We're checking the hospitals
找过纪念医院？    他不在那里
- Have you tried MemoriAL?
- He wouldn't be there
不，我是指医院没...
No, I mean...  Is it still...
那是卡丝工作的医院
It's Cathy's hospitAL
医院没被炸毁，但电话失灵
As far as l know it's still there,
but the phones are down
请你继续追查，麻烦你
All right. Can you keep checking?
Thanks
他们本可以发射巡航导弹
They could have launched
a cruise missile
不肯定是俄军所为    但也许是
- We don't know that this is Russia.
- We don't know it's not
若他们要我们知难而退
If they were sending us a message
那该会说这是他们做的
they'd want us to know it was them
除了他们想故弄玄虚，声东击西
Except they could inspire
the confusion we're going through now
总统先生，准备好通讯了
Mr President, we're uplinked
尼总统，美国发生严重核爆事件
President Nemerov, there's been a
major nuclear event in the United States
死伤惨重
Loss of life is severe
这绝不是意外    这绝不是意外
- It was no accident.
- It was not an accident
我们还不知道核弹从哪儿来...
We don't yet know where
it came from, we don't...
我们还没确定核弹的来源...
We have not yet ascertained the
source of this weapon. Rest assured...
我们还没确定核弹的来源
We have not yet ascertained
the source of this weapon
但可保证我国定将严惩真凶
But rest assured those responsible
will be deALt with most severely
他在试探我们
He's fishing
给他回覆
Send our reply
这么快有回应
Whoa, that was a little fast
请接受俄国人民最深切的慰问
"Please accept the deepest
sympathies of the Russian people."
若是蓄意施袭，诚是空前的暴行
"If it was deliberate,
this is a crime without precedent."
是哪个疯子所为？目的何在？
"What madman would do such a thing
and for what purpose?"
敬请相信俄国与此暴行绝无关连
"You must believe that Russia had
nothing to do with this infamous act."
是预谋，他早有此着
It's canned.
He prepared that in advance
尼总统，如今我们无理由怀疑
President Nemerov, we've no reason
to suspect Russian involvement...
俄国与此事有关
... at this time...
但我们会竭力自卫，免再受袭击
... but we will protect ourselves
from further aggression
他认为是我们做的
He thinks we did this
我们必须显示军力
We must demonstrate
the strength of our weapons
让他们明白攻打俄国就是找死
They have to understand that
attacking Russia would be suicide
加强戒备
Increase the alert status
接收到间断的讯号，方位020
TAO, EW. I'm picking up
intermittent radar, bearing 020
哪儿？
Where?
没有了
Now it's gone
这儿，但讯号微弱
There. It's a weak signAL
有敌机来袭
TAO, inbound contact
相同方位有多架敌机
Multiples on the same bearing
注意！    敌机迅速来袭
- Vampire, vampire!
- Fast movers inbound
有七、八、九架敌机！
I got seven, eight, nine of them!
导弹是从俄军战机发射的
The missiles definitely came
from Russian aircraft
母舰还保得住，但不能执行任务
Grennel thinks he can save the ship,
but flight ops are out
我没下令攻打母舰
I ordered no such attack
请保持冷静，先让我们调查清楚
You must not respond to this action
until we investigate all possibilities
先让我们调查清楚
"... until we investigate all possibilities."
正如车臣事件？
Like you did in Chechnya?
尼总统，谁在控制你的军队？
Mr President, who is in control
of your armed forces?
是你们在广岛投掷原子弹
You dropped the bomb on Hiroshima
是你们在长崎投掷原子弹
You dropped the bomb on Nagasaki
别拿车臣事件来教训我
Do not lecture me on Chechnya
拿车臣事件来教训我
"... lecture me on Chechnya."
事实上现在我们已跟俄国开战
Mr President, we are now at a
de facto state of war with the Russians
昨天勒约翰在海法，定要找到他
John Clark was in Haifa yesterday.
We have to find him right away
看看钆的含量读数
Wow.
Look at that gadolinium reading
质量数很高
Yeah. The mass fraction is huge
快联络迪伦，我会等
OK, connect me to Dillon. I'll hold
就在这儿，萨凡纳河
There it is. Savannah River
没错    什么没错？
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, yeah, what?
那边有钆的问题
They had a gadolinium problem
汉福的做法不对，产生太多i
Hanford does it another way,
and generate too much promethium
慢着，你可否解释清楚一点？
Hold on. Can you translate that
into English?
68年2月铀来自河上这间工厂
This plutonium came from the DOE
plant at Savannah River, February '68
源自K反应堆，还知道是哪部分
from K reactor. We even know
which part of K reactor
这是我们造的铀？    美国产品
- Wait. This is our plutonium?
- Made in the USA
迪伦，我一定要找到老卡
Dillon, you've got to find Cabot
你想说服我们发动第一击？
Are you advocating we launch
a first strike?
不是！已经有第一击，事已至此
It is not a first strike! There's ALready
been a first strike, and a second
你还不明白    我不明白
- Don't you get it?
- No, I don't get it!
为何要用核弹？这不合理
I don't understand why we have
to nuke them! It's not reasonable
悉尼，混帐！
Sidney, goddamn it!
他们打沉我们的航空母舰！
They practically sank
an aircraft carrier!
他们准备开战，老尼又废话连篇
Their missile silos are hot.
We're getting bulIshit from Nemerov
别忘了是谁先动手，他们要我死
Let's not forget how this started.
They tried to kill me, remember?
所以别劝我讲理！
Don't fucking tell me to be reasonable!
请来大厦旁边的鉴别分类营
Please come to the triage tent
on the side of the building
我们协助你找伤者
We will help you find
who you are looking for
但我们的血包供应不足
but we are low on blood supply
局长？
Sir?
你好
Hi
什么？
What?
总统？    他平安无恙
- President?
- The President's fine
他没事，局长...
He's fine. Sir...
那核弹，铀元素
The bomb. The plutonium...
太太    什么？
- Wife.
- What?
太太
Wife
你太太？她没事，在华盛顿
Your wife? I'm sure she's fine.
She's in DC
核爆范围不是...
The blast radius wasn't that...
那么大
... it wasn't that wide.
... it wasn't that wide
局长，听我说
Sir, listen to me
那些铀是我们的
The plutonium was ours
阿勒去追查军火商，我找不到他
John Clark's in Haifa to track down
the arms dealer. I can't get hold of him
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do
女... 女朋友
Girl... girlfriend
她...
She...
她在巴尔的摩工作，所以...
She works in BALtimore, so...
我不清楚
... I don't know
斯纳加
Spinnaker
什么？    斯纳加
- What?
- Spinnaker
局长？
Sir?
比利？
Bill?
我们查到接收货箱的人的地址
Yeah. We found the receiver address
for the crate
巴尔的摩港口，你可以去码头吗
Port of Baltimore.
Can you get to the docks?
找捷运货仓，收货人姓马
Find the Transcon warehouse.
The name on the manifest is Mason
对不起，我急需这部车
Sorry, I need this truck
老尼大怒，或有政变，美国收手
拜托
Come on
回覆
老卡已死，这是积克
68年被偷的铀，现在在哪里？
传送
混帐
Shit
斯纳加：以色列
以色列偷了铀？
斯纳加，不，是你们
还把它送给他们
总统，我们想到另一个对策
Sir, we've come up
with another ALternative
反攻发动袭击母舰的空军基地
A conventionAL attack on the airbase
where the carrier attack originated
有限度的还击    不用核武
- It's a measured response.
- Non-nuclear
够强烈吗    灵巧弹和F16战机
- Is it strong enough?
- Smart bombs and F-16s
我们绝不能示弱
Can't afford for them to see us as weak
要让他们知道我们绝不好惹的
They've got to know we have the guts
to take it to the next level
他们会明白这一点
I think they'll get that message
动手吧
Hit 'em
鹰巢，这是一号，我们瞄准目标
Eagles Nest, this is Eagle One.
We have target acquired. Target is lit
不作反击就等于坐以待毙
To make no response
is to invite a greater attack
诺福克和金斯湾的潜艇已出动
American submarines from Norfolk
and Kings Bay are putting to sea
载有D3三叉式导弹，第一击武器
They carry Trident D3 missiles.
A first strike weapon
老霍不会疯得发动第一击
Fowler is not so insane
as to launch a first strike
也许他不认为这是第一击
Perhaps he doesn't think
it's the first strike
他们出动轰炸机，我们就没选择
Once their SteALth bombers go up,
we will have no choice
这会是个徵兆
That will be the sign
怎么说服他别出动轰炸机？
How do we convince him
not to launch his bombers?
我们该...     导弹处于高度戒备
- Maybe we should...
- Bring our missiles to highest alert
那他们一定是疯了才会施袭
They'd be crazy to attack then
请各位注意
Can I have your attention?
发电机失灵
The generator has gone out
四处是玻璃碎，别乱动，我们...
There's broken glass everywhere. Stay
where you are. We will get back to...
好了，别乱动，我们会照料你们
OK, fine. Please, stay where you are.
We'll get you one by one
你听见吗？手脚有知觉吗？
Sir, can you hear me?
Can you feel your arms and legs?
9%静脉注射和吗啡滴注
A 9% IV and morphine drip
先生，我们会照顾你
Sir, we're gonna take care of you
这个伤者怎么样？
What have you got?
要是救不了的，应该怎么做？
What do we do with the ones
we know won't make it?
要是救不了的，应该怎么做？
What do we do with the ones
we know won't make it?
尽力而为
Whatever we can
什么事？
What?
卡比利死了
Bill Cabot died
我很难过
I'm really sorry
不会是这样的
This can't be happening
部长，兰利有电话来
Sir, we have a call from Langley
劳驾
Thank you
阿贝    这是雷积克
- Becker.
- This is Jack Ryan
太好了，是老尼的辩护者
Great. The Nemerov apologist
那核弹不是老尼的，我了解他
Sir, this bomb was not Nemerov.
I know this guy
车臣事件你也这么说，写报告吧
You said that after Grozny.
Put it in your report
那些铀...
The plutonium...
没想到这儿会出现辐射污染
Seems unusuAL to find
radiation poisoning here
这是前所未见的
I have never seen such a thing
所以我们在网上公布此事来求助
That is why we published the case
on the internet, to seek help
他说起因是什么？    他不肯说
- How did he say it happened?
- He will not tALk about it
其他人感染辐射令你病倒了？
Was anyone else exposed
to the materiALs that made you sick?
嘉先生，我不是警察
Mr Ghazi, I'm not the police
我是医生，我会保守秘密
I'm a physician. I assure you
anything you say stays between us
我朋友和我找到一个核弹
My friend and I find bomb
把它卖给一个军火商
We sell to a man
who buys such things
是这个人吗？
Was it this man?
其他人也许接触过这核弹
Other people may have come
in contact with that bomb
我们要救他们
We must help them
我... 快要死吗
I am... going to die?
是吗？
Yes?
是的
Yes
他叫奥森
His name is OIson
住在大马士革
He live in Damascus
行了，收到资料了
Oh, yeah. We're getting it all
核武攻斯普林斯可破坏北美空防
A nuclear strike on Colorado Springs
would take out NORAD
那他们就不能够还击
It would limit their ability
to launch a counter-attack
斯普林斯有多少人口？
How many people live
in Colorado Springs?
三、四十万人
Three or four hundred thousand
总统先生，用核武攻美国
Mr President, to use nuclear weapons
against the Americans...
就等于向他们宣战
... would be to cross a threshold
他们早已这么想，我们等什么？
They think we ALready have. Should
we now wait for them to annihilate us?
不是我惹的祸我阻止不了
I cannot stop what I did not start
总统先生，你要下令采取行动
Mr President, we need you
to initiate snapcount
然后呢？
What happens then?
用核武摧毁他们陆上的导弹基地
We prepare to take out their land-based
missiles with a nuclear strike
炸毁他们的潜艇或地上的飞机
find and kill their subs, knock out
the planes they have on the ground
还出动战机攻击已在空中的敌军
and mobilise our fighters to destroy
the ones they ALready have in the air
胜算有多大？
What are our chances?
大卫？
David?
我们会令老尼陷于困境
Odds are we leave Nemerov
in a pretty pickle
他剩下的核弹最多有几百个
He'll be left with, at best,
a few hundred nukes
那是我们找不到的
the ones we can't find
它们较小型，易运送，没那么准
Mostly the... smaller, more mobile,
less accurate kind
而它们的目标会是我们的城市
All those can do is target our cities
但他心知我们一定会以眼还眼
But he knows to an absolute certainty
that we will respond against his cities
我毕生想做一个总统
I spent my entire adult life
wanting to be president
任期就此结束
This is my presidency?
他会留三百个核弹以备不时之需
Sir, I think he'll keep his 300 nukes as a
deterrent against any future aggressor
这晚他应该会暂时就此罢手
I think he'll push back from the table
and call it a night
我下令采取行动，准备用核武
I'm giving the order for snapcount.
Maximum readiness
奥森收到斯拿4500万的汇款
OIson had wire payments of $45 million
from someone named Dressler
奥森收到斯拿4500万的汇款
OIson had wire payments of $45 million
from someone named Dressler
快查这人底细... 积克，你快走
Dillon, find out who Dressler is.
Jack, I want you out of there
我在码头    调查这个斯拿
- l'm at the docks.
- Look for the name Dressler
积克你快走... 给巴市警局这地址
No. Jack, get out. Dillon, call the
BALtimore PD, give them the address
等警察来    我会再联络你
- Wait for the cops.
- I'll call you back
斯拿是什么人？
Who's Dressler?
斯拿在哪里？可恶！
Where is he, goddamn it?
斯拿在哪里？
Where is Dressler?
警察！举高双手！
Police! Put your hands up!
斯拿在哪里？    你是雷积克？
- Where's Dressler?
- Are you Jack Ryan?
斯拿在哪里？    放手
- Where's Dressler, goddamn it?
- Let him go!
斯拿在哪里？快说？
Where's Dressler? Where is he?
兰利说你需要帮助
Langley said you might need help
我要去国防部    我可以帮你忙
- I gotta get to the Pentagon.
- I think I can help you with that
总统先生
Mr President
他们的轰炸机已离开阿维艾诺
Their SteALth bombers
have left Aviano
他们有所行动
That is the sign
快把它们击落
Shoot them down
愿主保佑
God protect us
他们的战机紧急起飞，时间无多
Mr President, they're scrambling
their fighters. We're out of time
大卫！    他心脏病发
- Dave!
- He has a heart condition
快找医生    总统先生
- Get a doctor.
- Mr President
你的药呢    我说叫医生来
- Where's your nitro?
- I said get a doctor!
总统先生    扶他去我的房间
- Mr President.
- Take him to my quarters
上校，拿系统密码机来
Colonel, bring in the launch codes
斯拿是奥地利商人，是亿万富翁
Dressler's an Austrian manufacturer,
billionaire
他父亲在纽伦堡被处决
His father was executed at Nuremberg
他买到国会议席
He bought a seat in parliament
但因说了拥护纳粹言论而被撵走
and got
booted out for saying pro-Nazi things
快让我跟总统说清楚
Rudy, get me through to the President
不行，他们正采取核武行动
I can't do it, Jack.
They're in the snapcount
没法联络他们    废话
- There's no way in.
- BulIshit
让我帮你    不，卡上有泥巴
- I can do that for you, sir.
- No, it's fine. Got some dirt on it
给我看，现在高度戒备    我知
- Can I see it? We're on high alert.
- I understand
先生，把卡放下    退后
- Sir, put the card down.
- Back off
我命令你...     退后
- I am ordering you...
- Back off!
快停手！我命令你快停手！
Step back now! I am ordering
you to take a step back! Put...
上将，中情局的雷积克来了
GenerAL, there's a Dr Ryan
from the CIA
他要求进入NMCC，他独自来的
He wants to enter NMCC.
He's unescorted
他想怎样？    见你
- What's he want?
- You, sir
我要传达卡局长的口信给总统
I have a message from Director Cabot
that I need to transmit over the hotline
谁批准你这样做？    没有人
- What's your authorisation?
- I don't have one
卡局长呢？    他已死了
- Where's Cabot?
- Cabot's dead, sir
我要传口信
- I need to get this information sent
要先得批准，带他走
- Not without authorisation. Get him out
上将！总统根据错误情报下决定
Wait! GenerAL! The President is basing
his decisions on bad information!
若你不理我，你和我的家人
If you shut me out,
your family and my family
和2500万家庭会在半小时内丧命
and 25 million other families
will be dead in 30 minutes
我的职责是给决策者准确的情报
My orders are to get this information
to the people who make the decisions
我只是想传达情报
I just need to send some information
总统为什么要听你说？
What makes you think
the President will listen to you?
他没此必要
He doesn't have to
轰炸机有多接近？
How close are the bombers?
它们进出波兰上空
They're slipping in and out of radar
over Poland
出动导弹兵团
Activate the missile regiments
系统在你下令后一分钟才启动
The launch sequence takes a minute
to process after you give the order
下令前，要先核对身分
Before the order can be taken,
an ID check must be performed
我的号码是...
Mine is the...  My number is...
数下来... 第三个号码
... the third one... third number down
from the top
你的命令是什么？
Your orders, sir?
出击    抱歉，总统？
- Strike.
- I'm sorry, sir?
我下令出击
I give the order to strike
要马上作两人授命，下令出击
Under the two-man rule, the order
to strike must now be confirmed
罗拔，看在老天份上
Bob, for the love of God
动手好了
Just do it
国务卿奥悉尼，第四个号码
Sidney Owens, Secretary of State.
It's the fourth number down
已作了两人授命，下令出击
The order to strike has now been
confirmed by the two-man rule
出击的命令已确定，启动系统
NMCC, strike order has been
confirmed. Start the sequence
热线有动静    早已给他们机会
- We've got activity on the hotline.
- They've had their chance
不，有人在跟老尼通话
No, somebody's tALking to the Kremlin
说“美国是恐怖袭击的受害者”
It says, "America has been the victim
of a terrorist attack."
你应该想像得到我方有不少揣测
As you can imagine, there has
been much confusion here...
人心惶惶
... and fear
但我们知道不是俄国动武
But we know the weapon
was not Russian
“但我们知道不是俄国动武”
"But we know the weapon
was not Russian."
怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
照我说的打
Type exactly what I say
你究竟是谁？
Who are we tALking to?
积克，我跟局长在莫斯科见过你
Ryan. I met you in Moscow with
Bill Cabot.
今天他在巴尔的摩死了
He died today in BALtimore
中止通讯    已启动核武系统
- Cut him off.
- Launch sequence has begun
两个月前
Two months ago
新法西斯主义者斯拿买了原子弹
a neo-fascist named Dressler bought
an A-bomb on the black market
中止通讯    无法中止系统操作
- Cut him off.
- The system can't be cut off
那快找人阻止他
Then get someone to stop him
他雇用三个俄罗斯...
- He paid three disaffected Russian...
科学家修复原子弹
- "scientists to make the bomb active."
然后把它送来美国，一个姓马的
"He shipped it to the US,
where a man named Mason"
是他搞鬼，令我们两国起纷争
was hired to deliver the bomb and
set our countries on a collision course
胡说八道，他是中情局
This is madness. He is CIA
我们绝不能听信他们的间谍
We cannot hang our fate
on the word of their spy
听多一点没害处吧？
What is the harm of listening
a bit more?
你想我怎么做？
What are you asking of me?
就此罢手
Back down
有什么可保证霍总统也会收手？
What guarantee do I have that
President Fowler will follow suit?
没有保证
None
看见吗？他在浪费时间
You see? He is wasting time
我们得出击，时间无多
We must launch now.
We have only moments
我知道你跟巴尔的摩的核爆无关
Sir, I know you had nothing to do
with the BALtimore bomb
你也知道，但你还是要攻打我们
and you know you didn't, but you're
still about to launch a nuclear strike
说够了    这都是恐惧之故
- Yes, sir. That's all, Dr Ryan.
- This is about fear
害怕你们的导弹，我们的潜艇
Fear of your missiles,
fear of our subs
害怕做弱者，害怕犯错
Fear of being weak,
of making a mistake
害怕对方率先制造这些烂核弹！
the fear of the other guy that had us
build these bombs in the first place!
没通讯了
It stopped
他们中止了他的通讯
They cut him off
他们会出击
They are going to strike
准备启动核武系统
Prepare the launch orders now
30秒后发射
30 seconds to launch
老天... 总统先生？
Oh, my God. Mr President?
我下令...
俄国战略部队撤消战备状态
暂时我们会保持在防卫戒备状态
We will maintain our defensive alert
for the moment
但是已撤退攻击部队
but our offensive forces
are withdrawn
“若你照这样做”
"If you match this,
“我建议双方撤消备战状态”
I propose a phased
mutuAL stand down over five hours."
关闭核武系统
Stop the launch sequence
这是莱上将，马上关闭核武系统
Lasseter here. Flash override.
Stop the sequence!
撤走战机，进入三级紧急状态
Order the planes to stand down.
Take us to DEFCON-3
找人问积克我可以用电话了吗？
And would somebody ask Mr Ryan
if I can use the phone now?
你还在这儿
You're still here
美国
俄罗斯
没有什么比我们今周所做的
There is no more fitting memoriAL
for those who perished in this tragedy
更能悼念这次惨剧的受害者
than the steps we've taken this week
以求多国通力合作
toward a multinational campaign
大规模销毁破坏力强大的军备
to root out and eliminate
weapons of mass destruction
我们有此目标
We embarked on this course
全因吸取了重大的教训
because
we have learned, at too great a cost
明白到若我们动用最强大的武器
that if the most powerful weapons
ever created are unleashed
那不是因为愤恨，而是恐惧之故
they will be fired not in anger,
but in fear
雷博士
Dr Ryan
古先生
Mr Grushkov
今天... 是个大好日子
It is... a lovely day
对
Yeah
抱歉，这是...     梅医生，幸会
- I'm sorry, this is...
- Dr Muller. How do you do?
幸会
Nice to meet you
为何我不为此感到意外？
Why am I not surprised
you know her name?
我们的朋友比利以为我是个间谍
Our friend William thought
I was a spy
当然他无法证实这个
Of course, he could never prove it
他从未说过你们是朋友
He never told me you were friends
也许他跟你不太熟络
Maybe he didn't know you well enough
他说他有个俄罗斯线人
He told me he had a source in Russia
“打开秘密渠道”？
"To keep the back channels open?"
“以免灾难发生”
"In hopes of staving off disaster."
甘尼迪说过我们最大的共通之处
Kennedy said,
"Our most basic common link"
就是同居住于这地球上
"is that we all inhabit
this small planet. "
呼吸相同的空气
"We all breathe the same air. "
大家都重视儿女的将来
"We all cherish our children's future...  "
还有我们生有尽时
"... and we're all mortal. "
我会好怀念... 跟比利合作的日子
I will miss... so very much
tALking to William
我也是
Me too
也许日后有机会
Perhaps from time to time
我们可以合作
you and I can tALk
乐意之至
Yeah, I'd like that
这是什么？
What is this?
庆祝你们订婚的小礼物
A modest gift for your engagement
他... 今早才向我求婚
He... he just asked me this morning
我们还没告诉任何人
We haven't told anybody about it
你怎么可能知道？
How... how could you possibly know?